Daniel Patnode

Seattle WA-98126 || 206-388-8618 || dbpatnode@gmail.com Github: dbpatnode || Medium : @danielpatnode || LinkedIn : daniel patnode

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Full stack web developer with experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in scientific glass blowing and organic agriculture. Possess strong skills in team-building, project management and interpersonal communication that would help any sized team progress in a constructive and positive fashion.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, RESTful API, MVC models, Postgres, Active Record, HTML, CSS, BootStrap, VScode

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Brew Maps - Github | Demo

Brewery journaling application that allows users to favorite, rate and write reviews of breweries across the United States.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Maintained an extensive API through use of OpenBreweryDB's external API to pull data from more than 900 breweries across the United States, as well creating custom seed data.
- Implemented MapBox (Ubers map service) to render breweries on a map with custom pins and cards.

FavFest - Github || Demo

Festival and artist tracking app that allows users to view festivals and their related artists as well as add them to their wishlist and write comments.

- Followed proper MVC practices RESTful routes to create a fully integrated Rails frontend and backend with authentication.
- Added custom validations for login and signup which added increased security.
- Embedded seeded Youtube links that rendered fully interactive videos on rendered pages.
- Formed a functional search engine that allows users to narrow down their entries based on genre, name and location.

Oasis - Github | Demo

Allows users find and add hidden rooftop areas to their favorites and displays them on a map.

- Executed a rails backend API with custom seed data and vanilla javascript front end to create a single page application.
- Employed Google maps API to render hidden rooftop parks across the Seattle and San Francisco area.
- Worked collaboratively with a group of 4 to hit project goals in a timely fashion.

EXPERIENCE

QCB Seattle, WA Scientific Glass Blower March 2015 - October 2020

- Collaborated with upper management to identify and increase productivity of training programs for new employees resulting in smoother onboarding processes, increased overall productivity and higher cleanliness.
- Implemented lean processing of raw materials leading to a 30% reduction of material loss.
- Designed and advanced new prototypes through R&D leading to several products going to market.
- Troubleshot ill working lathe equipment leading to less money spent on external lathe technicians.

Seattle Tilth Alliance Mentor and Facilitator

Issaquah, Washington May 2014 - Present

- Empowered 15-20 students weekly to co-create an educational experience in relation to ecosystems, food processing and environmental impacts of large-scale farming.
- Facilitated workshops on topics related to organic farming and how attendees could improve their eco footprint.
- Provided a safe environment to encourage, motivate and engage incoming at-risk youth from the United Way Mentees program and
 individualized programming to strengthen collaboration skills using visualization, repetition and stimulating activities.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Seattle, Washington June 2020 - October 2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Pullman, Washington

Washington State University
Bachelor of Science in Agricultural and Food Sciences; Organic Agriculture & GreenHouse Management

June 2014